Hello everyone, in this session, I will demo how to generate Testcase using GitHub Copilot.
To use this feature, first, I need to have Test Workspace Folder created for the item I need to generate Testcase.
In this session, I will go to Team Support. Here, I will have two options.
The first option is to create Test Workspace Folder for an item.
And the second option is to create Test Workspace Folder for a list of other items.
I will demo the first option first. I will choose One Item here.
Here, I will have three different types of information.
The first information is the Test Workspace Folder.
The first information is the database path.
This is the folder path that contains the database that I have logged from the stream or snapshot.
The second information is the workspace path.
I will create a blank folder.
And I will take this folder path to contain the outputs in the Tool running process.
The third information is the item name.
This is the name of the item that I need to create.
The Test Workspace Folder.
After I have filled out these three things, I will click on Generate Environment.
After completing this step, Tool will show an option to notify.
At the same time,
Visual Studio Code will automatically open and save the space folder of the item you need to create.
Here I will have the source file.
I will also have two files.
The first is test.cpp and the second is test.h.
Here they are.
Besides, I can use the "Open output" feature.
It will help me to open and save the space folder of the item I need to create.
For the second option, I will choose ListItem.
I also have three important information.
The first is database path.
The second one is the first option.
And the third one is ListItem path.
I will have an Excel file to store the information of the item name and item path.
I also need to create a SpaceFolder.
Then I will take the path of this file and store it in Visual Studio Code.
I need to open it to the third path.
Then I will click on "Generate environment".
After this step is done,
choose OpenOutput
Then we will see the workspace folder is created
Inside Itemlist
After having the test workspace folder for item
We need to create testcase
We choose Generate Test Case by A.I. Copilot
Here, I have two main sources of information
The first one is the item path
I will go to the Test Workspace Folder of an item
called Generate Test Case
For example, this item
I will copy the path of this file
After that, I will input the first source of information
And the next one is the database path
Just like the previous step
I will also input the data of the folder containing the database
Here, then I will click Auto define object here
In the process of running
I can
follow the information directly
by clicking on the Show Execution Log here
There is a Terminal window that will appear
and will show the information
while the Tool is running
At the end of Auto Default Check, we will go to the next step, which is Prepare Get SUTs.
In the pop-up information, we will see that it found 3 SUTs functions and update dropdown.
We see that there are 3 functions listed here.
We will select one of the 3 functions that we want to generate test case.
In the next step, we will have 2 options.
The first option is to generate test case for the function we are selecting here.
And the second option is to generate test case for all functions in this item.
To make it easier for us to observe the running process,
while generating test case, we will open Visual Studio Code
And import the test workspace folder of item inside here.
So we demonstrate the first option,
and generate test case for only one function here, we choose generate one SUT
We can see the trigger generate testcase is sent here
We will see the information in the Visual Studio Code.
We will go to Output and choose GitHub Copilot Chat here.
The generate process information will be shown in this terminal.
After we see the notification that the test generation is completed,
that is, the generate process is done.
Next, we will click on Terminal.
We will build this test.
Here we have 8 Testcases and all 8 Testcases are passed.
Next, we will see how the code coverage is.
Then we will proceed to build Cantata for this test.
We will click on Build Cantata here.
After building Cantata is done,
we will see that in the
Test Workspace folder of the item,
we will see that there is a Cantata folder in the Output folder.
We will open Cantata.
Click on Tools.
Then we will go to the C folder.
Choose TCC.
Go to Tools.
Go to Cantata.
Then we will open this tool.
We will create a project in Cantata.
C Project.
We will name the project,
like the Item name
We will drag the folder Cantata to the new project we've just created in Cantata tool
I will click on this .cov file
Then I will open this file
Here I see that the first function
the code color are blue
This is equivalent to the fact that this light code has been covered
And these red lines are still not covered
Then I will demonstrate my second option
is Generate Testcase All SUT
Before clicking on this Generate button
I will delete the newly created Testcases
In the first option
to avoid being duplicated for the next run time
Then I will click on Generate Testcase All SUT here
to create Testcases for all functions in this item
After finished generating the testcases for 3 functions in this item, I will build the Cantata
In this step, we can click on the "Build Cantata" button to build in Tool
Or we can build Cantata from the Visual Studio Code
I go to Terminal, select Runtasks, and select "Cantata++ coverage measurement"
In the Terminal section, I can see the values and code coverage has reached 100%
We will go to Tool Cantata
We will see that the code had been covered 100%
I will gradually drag the Cantata folder into the project
in Cantata tool
Here we can see that the line code of these three functions of this item are already covered
And so the color of these changes into green
Now we click on Cantata, choose View, choose Report Viewer to view this report
We can view the test report here
And the coverage that we can see here
This is the end of my demonstration
Thank you for watching